Coordonnées

www.linkedin.com/in/nguyen-phuc-9a40a5113 (LinkedIn)

Principales compétences

Architects
Symfony Framework
Ruby on Rails

Nguyen Phuc

Senior Software Engineer Ho Chi Minh-Ville, Viêt Nam

Résumé

I am a Software Engineer with 7 years of experience in software development industry. During that time, I have been working and developing web and applications in various domains including e-commerce, e-learning, cloud office, data report tools, SaaS, internal business operation tools & so on...

By continuously practicing and training, I've found myself being very proactive and efficient in programming and designing application for both high and low levels. My favorite and most trusted language once was PHP but understand that any software can be written in any language and I just need to make the right choice. With that though, I extend my pool of knowledge to: Ruby, NodeJS, Python, Go, Bash to enrich my experience and also gain the chance to explore the strength of other languages.

Currently, I am in charge of a small development team (3 developers & 1 QC) for the freelance business and looking for any SMB projects, feel free to contact me.

Expérience

CreditorWatch
Senior Software Engineer
mai 2023 - Present (1 an 11 mois)
Vietnam

SnowSolutions
Senior Software Engineer & Solution Architect
juin 2022 - août 2023 (1 an 3 mois)
Vietnam

SECOMM

6 ans 1 mois

Solutions Architect

décembre 2020 - décembre 2022 (2 ans 1 mois)

Vietnam

- Join discovery sessions and explore client business requirements
- Analyze business requirements and provide solutions
- Provide detailed estimation and technical approach as a complete quotation
- Develop core features. Breakdown epics and distribute task to others
- Control code quality from outsourcing partners
- Plan & design trainning roadmap
- Optimize development team process
- Research and apply latest technologies to active tools & projects
- Host technical workshops for development team to keep knowledge update & open opportunities to share and learn

Senior Software Engineer

décembre 2016 - décembre 2020 (4 ans 1 mois)

Vietnam

- Develop features, functionalities base on client's demand
- Develop & integrate payments, delivery methods to e-commerce websites
- Integrate ERP, CRM, IMS to e-commerce websites
- Migrate project data using data bridge, SQL script
- Build & Deploy CI/CD process
- Build & Deploy automation test, unit test
- Learn, research and replicate code structure, design patterns in custom project
- Manage small team with 8 developers, control team workload, tasks.
 Monitoring & resolve team conflicts. Review and revise team's pull request

Gramia

Software Engineer

janvier 2019 - janvier 2020 (1 an 1 mois)

Vietnam

- Define product functionalities & compose product spec documentations
- Design product data structures & define potential product's techstack
- Design source code structure
- Develop product foundation & implement core features
- Research & apply Enneagram doctrine. Convert related logics into software program
- Research solution to build up a SaaS platform

Formation

HCM University Of Technology (HUTECH)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering · (2013 - 2017)